A documentary film by Gary Hustwit
Urbanized is a documentary film directed by Gary Hustwit.
A documentary about the design of cities, which looks at the issues and strategies behind urban design and
features some of the world's foremost architects, planners, policymakers, builders, and thinkers.
Self, played by Norman Foster.
Self, played by Jan Gehl.
Self, played by Ellen Dunham-Jones.
Self, played by Amanda M. Burden.
Self, played by Joshua David.
Self, played by Oscar Niemeyer.
Urbanized is a documentary film directed by Gary
Hustwit and released on 26 October 2011.
It is considered the third of a three-part series on design known as the Design Trilogy; the first being
Helvetica, about the typeface, and the second being Objectified, about industrial design.
The documentary discusses how cities are designed, and it features interviews with
urban planners and architects, such as Oscar Niemeyer and Jan Gehl.
The film explores themes of designer, urban sprawl, urban.